Richard Parle

Wirral, Merseyside 07545879803 richardparle@gmail.com

Profile

I have always had a passion for computers and technology, and Northcoders was suggested as a route to take due to its reputation as one of the leading bootcamps in the country. For the previous 8 years I worked as the lead Operations Co-Ordinator for Menzies Distribution. This role taught me a lot about problem solving in a highly stressful and fast paced environment, which I believe will aid me greatly as a Software Developer.

Personal Portfolio

https://rp-portfolio.netlify.app

Skills

Front-end: Javascript, React, React Native, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap.

Back-end: Node, Express, SQL, Firebase

Testing: Jest

Employment History

Full Stack Developer (Northcoders)

02/2022 - 05/2022

Northcoders is a 13-week intensive course learning full stack development, learning testing driven development using Jest. Front-end using Javascript and back-end using Node and SQL. I also learned to use frameworks/libraries such as Express and Bootstrap.

Operations Co-Ordinator (Menzies Distribution)

11/2013 - 12/2021

- Producing and analysing weekly KPI reports.
- Raising purchase orders.
- Ensuring loads meet safety standards.
- Driver management and engagement.
- Complying with all transport legislations.
- Using a variety of systems for end-to-end supply chain data inputting.

Customer Relations Advisor (Barclays Bank)

09/2011 - 10/2013

- Redress calculations for Loans, Mortgages and Overdrafts.
- Speaking with customers to discuss their complaints.
- Training new starters and assisting them through their accreditation period.
- Quality assurance checking.

Customer Service Adviser (The Contact Company)

07/2010 - 09/2011

- Manage large amounts of inbound calls in a timely manner.
- Identify customer needs, clarify information, research every issue and provide solutions.
- Build sustainable relationships and engage customers by taking the extra mile.
- Meet personal/team qualitative and quantitative targets.

Education

The Open University 09/2019 – 07/20 CertHE in Computing & IT

Wirral Met College 09/2007 – 07/09 Diploma in Anatomy and Physiology Diploma in Nutrition

Bebington High School 09/01 – 07/07 10 GCSE's Grade A-C

- References available upon request -